CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Meerun Zahur

Date of Birth: 6th May 1976

Place of Birth: Chelsea, London

Email: <u>zahurmeerun@hotmail.com</u>

Phone number: +23057075200

Zahur Meerun

Junior FullStack Developer

Full Stack Software Developer, newly graduated, with skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python. Able to complement these technical skills with a professional background within the aviation industry. I'm a career switcher, formerly a commercial airline pilot with 15 years' of experience as a First Officer, with a first degree in Civil Engineering.

Creative, focused and committed to the technical industry.

GITHUB

LINKEDIN

EDUCATION:

• 2020-21: Diploma in FullStack Software Development, Code Institute

• **2006-07**: **Frozen ATPL**, 43 AIRSCHOOL(SA)

• 2002-04: MSc Project Management, University Of Mauritius

• 1995-99: Bachelor of Civil Engineering (Honours), University of Mauritius

CORE SOFTWARE SKILLS:

• Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React

Backend: Python, Node.js

• Frameworks: Flask, Django, Bootstrap, Materialize

• Database: SQL, MongoDB

• Source control: Git

• **UI/UX:** Wireframe

• **Deployment:** Heroku, AWS, S3

SOFTWARE PROJECTS:

Project 1: Tourism Site, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4

- Project 2: Stars wars themed memory game, HTML, CSS, Bootsrap 4, Javascript
- <u>Project 3</u>: Art selling website, HTML, CSS, Materialize, Javascript, MongoDB,
 Flask, Python
- <u>Project 4:</u> Online food and delivery service, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript,
 SQL, Django, Python, Stripe, JQuery
- <u>Project 5:</u> StarWars character search, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, SQL,
 Django, Python, JQuery
- <u>Project 6:</u> Quiz application using Employee Number, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap,
 Javascript, SQL, Django, Python, JQuery
- <u>Project 7:</u> Software to manage employee sick and annual leave, HTML, CSS,
 Bootstrap, Javascript, SQL, Django, Python, JQuery

WORK EXPERIENCE:

1. Air Mauritius

2008-Present First Officer Total Flying hours: 7500

| | First officer |
|------|---------------|---------------|---------------|---------------|---------------|
| | Atr-72 | A319 | A340 | A330 | A350 |
| Year | 2008-2011 | 2011-2013 | 2011-2017 | 2015-Present | 2017-Present |

2. Fitzpatrick Construction UK 2004-2005

Assistant Site Manager

Assistant site manager for a school expansion project in Morden, London. Duties involved management of resources for a steel/concrete school expansion on a daily basis. I was also involved with safety regulation implementation.

3. LTA Construction 2003-2004

Site Manager/Assistant Project Manager

Site manager supervising civil works for the super market chain Super U (Mauritius) and also assistant project manager for a new build cold storage for the fruit supplier Surat.

Main duties involved dealing with the client from conception stage of projects, design process, tendering and management of different contractors (civil, mechanical etc...) until completion of the project.

4. Compagnie Mauricienne De Textile Projects (CMT) 1999-2003

Trainee Engineer/Assistant Site Manager

Assistant site manager for several projects for CMT involving new build and renovation works located at La Tour Koenig, Phoenix, Verdun and Montagne Blanche.

Main duties involved design of concrete structures and management of in house and appointed contractors for the construction of steel frame buildings. I was also involved in the tender process and civil maintenance of existing buildings.